Omkar Savalkar

Front End Developer

Computer Software Engineer having strong work experience of 1.6 years as Front end developer with proven quick learning, best performing and team player ability. Have knowledge of working on web application development projects from scratch using frontend react skills during job tenure and seeking for more opportunitities in a reputed firm.

Website: https://omkar-ownwebapp.vercel.app

EXPERIENCE

Xoriant Solutions Pvt. Ltd (Product-Service), Pune, Maharashtra **Software Engineer**

August 2021 - Present

- Contributed and developed the UI code from scratch using React, typescript and Material UI.
- Responsible for integrating 40% Rest API's involved with the front end.
- Presented and demonstrated 3 successful workflow demos to clients.
- Worked on debugging, code bug fixes and resolving code issues.
- Implemented enhancements at later stages in less span as per requirement.

INTERNSHIP

HealByUs Android Application, Pune, Maharashtra *Developer*

June 2020 - Aug 2020

 Worked on a complete project and actively contributed in planning, UI design, development and testing with the team.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Navigation for Visually Impaired (AI, Computer Vision), Remote Developer

July 2020 - May 2021

• Coded and developed 50% of the project and after research used ML libraries which also gave good performance.

Forum Solutions (Android Application), Remote Developer

August 2019 - December 2019

• Designed and developed a complete mobile application using Android Studio and Firebase.

Address:- Pune, Maharashtra,

India. 411062

Mobile No:- +91-9766112890

Email:-

omkarsavalkar22@gmail.com

Linkedin:-

https://www.linkedin.com/in/omkar-savalkar

Github profile:-

https://github.com/OmkarSa

<u>valkar</u>

SKILLS

React

Javascript

Typescript

Material UI

Redux

Next Js

HTML

CSS

SASS

Node Js (Basic)

EDUCATION

Nutan Maharashtra Institute of Engineering and Technology

Bachelor of Computer Engineering

June 2021

Pune, Maharashtra

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Achieved Xoriant Spot Award for Best Performance in team (Xoriant Solutions).
- 1st prize for Final Year Project in (UGCON) 2021